when looking for a weight bench for a
home gym most people are going to want
to Target an adjustable one like the rep
Fitness 83 000 due to its versatility
this bench is rated to hold up to a
thousand pounds of weight it's made from
11 gauge steel it has built-in leg
rollers and it's a full FID bench I've
been using this bad boy a whole lot
lately so why don't we go ahead and
break down my experience
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video I've got the rep Fitness AB 3000
N4 review now if you don't know how this
works in this video today I'm going to
tell you everything you need to know
about this weight bench from the price
and the features as well as some pros
and cons and of course who should or
maybe should not purchase this weight
bench now before I get going with all of
that I gotta let you know we've reviewed
a ton of weight benches on barbin.com so
if you want to browse our best list just
go and search bar band best weight
benches and you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
best
[Music]
all right so I want to talk about what I
like about the rep Fitness AB 3000 and I
got to kick this off with the money so
this bench is available for right around
320 bucks which is a super solid deal in
my opinion considering it is an FID
bench and it is made from 11 gauge steel
So for anybody who does not know what an
FID bench is or you know what that
stands for stands for flat and client
and Decline and that's referring to the
positions of the back pad right here so
in my opinion this is a complete Game
Changer in terms of chest development
specifically because you are able to do
both incline and decline presses but
that's also going to be really nice when
you're going to do some shoulder presses
as well and you're able to have some
support on your back I also really like
the leg rollers right here you know this
is going to be really nice as you're in
that decline position it's going to keep
your body you know where it needs to be
you're not going to slide down the bench
which definitely would not be fun and
this is kind of a cherry on top for me
because you know most of the time you're
going to have to pay extra for an
attachment or just for that feature in
general and it's really nice that it's
you know included with that purchase and
a pretty low price tag if I'm being
completely honest with you and you know
once again this bench does have a weight
capacity of a thousand pounds which is
obviously a really high number but
especially you know once you factor in
that price tag for this bench and the
same goes with 11 gauge steel so most of
the time you know a bench with this
price tag is going to have 14 gauge
steel which is still nice don't get me
wrong but 11 gauge steel is most likely
what you're going to find in a
commercial gym setting so that's really
nice you know you're kind of getting
that feeling in your own personal home
gym so in terms of adjustments you have
eight different back pad angles five
different angles for your seat pad and
you have six different angles for the
leg roller you know that way you're
always able to switch up your workouts
and hit your muscles from various angles
which that's a really nice thing I also
think it's really cool how the leg
roller right here has a handle for you
to grab and it's going to make it really
easy for you to move around your
personal space especially since this
bench only weighs about 90 pounds
all right now to be completely honest
with you guys I don't have a whole lot
of cons when it comes to this weight
bench but there's still two that you
know some people may experience so I got
to bring them up first of all we need to
talk about the gap between the two pads
right here now it's not that bad you
know this is obviously a really common
thing among weight benches you know off
the top of my head there's only one
bench I can think of that does not have
a gap whatsoever and that's the rep
Fitness ab5000 that I reviewed a while
back for you guys now this is not a you
know deal breaker for me it's really not
even that annoying or that much to deal
with it's just something you know worth
mentioning because as you go to lay down
you're doing you know some flat bench
press whatever it is you can kind of
feel that on your lower back a little
bit and I think you'll get used to it
it's just something worth mentioning and
I know I've been ranting and raving
about how good of a deal this weight
bench is I still think that's true but
you know 320 bucks for just a weight
inch could be a lot for some people and
you can certainly find some cheaper ones
out there online they just probably
aren't going to be made from 11 gauge
steel and they might not last you as
long as this bench will
foreign
[Music]
okay so I want to touch on price one
more time before we move on with the
rest of this video once again the rep
Fitness ab3000 is priced for right
around 320 bucks and I think this is a
really solid deal you know considering
what you're going to get out of this
bench you know 11 gauge steel the
built-in leg roller it's an FID bench
you got to get that thousand pound
weight capacity this is a really nice
deal but you know if you don't want to
spend 320 bucks up front rep is going to
allow you to finance this purchase and
you can pay you know for it monthly if
you want to shipping is also free with
this bench which is you know really nice
touch in my opinion and you know once
again you can definitely find some
cheaper benches out there but be
completely honest with you guys I think
you're going to be extremely
hard-pressed to find a better deal with
a weight bench it's going to last you as
long as this one will
[Music]
all right now let's take a second and
talk about the build and you know some
of the features with this weight bench
once again it only weighs 90 pounds so
it's super easy for you to move it
around your personal space but you know
it's really sturdy you know I'm sitting
here you know rocking back and forth
it's not moving it's really nice I also
really like this front foot design right
here it's pretty narrow you know it
doesn't jut out to the sides or anything
it's not going to get in the way of your
feet or you know make you feel
uncomfortable as you're laying down to
do your bench presses for example once
again this bench is made from 11 gauge
steel which is of the highest quality
you could ask for it to be so it's going
to last you a super long time the
padding right here is pretty firm you
know it definitely provides support that
you need when you're doing your workouts
but it's not too firmed or it's
uncomfortable to lay on and the padding
is also really easy to clean you know
you can just use a disinfectant wipe
maybe some Lysol you know whatever
disinfectant spray it's it's super easy
for you to clean and it has a footprint
of about eight square feet or so which
is honestly pretty common in terms of
weight benches now when it comes to the
features I want to talk about the leg
roller first this is a really nice touch
you know it's going to be great as
you're going to do you know your
anything where the back pad is in that
decline position we also have six
different angles right here with that
leg roller for you to work with it's
really nice and you also have a built-in
handle right here that way you know you
can always grab it and move the bench
around and also I like that because it's
really easy for you to grab it at any
given moment with the back pad you have
eight different angles and as you can
see right here there's laser cut degree
markings that way you always know you
know exactly what degree you know you're
working with and that's going to come in
handy you know as you're doing you know
your incline bench press your shoulder
press you know whatever you're wanting
to do that's going to be really nice and
with the seat pad you have five
different angles for you to work with
there's a pop pin on the other side
right here just pull it out and this is
going to adjust really easy for you
[Music]
all right so let's go ahead and kind of
break everything down up close for you
guys and just kind of demonstrate how
everything works let's talk about this
padding first you know this is really
firm but in a good way it's not going to
be uncomfortable for you to lay down on
it still you know provides it provides
optimal support whenever you're working
out and it's really easy for you to
clean now let's talk about adjustments
it's really easy to adjust this bench
I'm going to go ahead and grab there's a
handle right here on both sides I'm
going to go ahead and do that but you
don't necessarily have to you could let
that fall if you want but as you see you
know you've got all your laser cut
degree markings right here that way you
know exactly you know what angle
everything is whenever you're going to
work out that's really nice you know
like zero is perfect for a flat bench 45
degrees is great when you're going to do
an incline press
and right here it really at 60 is gonna
be great when you're going to do
shoulder presses that way you know you
have that nice support on your back and
you're still able to hit you know your
shoulders right there now it doesn't say
what this is right here this decline
position but that's negative 12 degrees
just so you already know what that is
and then there you go now let's move up
to this seat pad right here something
really cool with this with this pad
right here is that you can actually
reverse it so let's say you would prefer
to have this you know narrow portion
right here on the front you can do that
you can definitely flip it around if you
want to now
you have five different angles with this
seat pad and once again you have a pot
pan on the back right here you just pull
it out and you're able to adjust it
however you want now here's something to
talk about so you have this Gap right
here in between these two pads right
well you know that's pretty annoying
especially when you're going to do this
decline so that's why this comes in
handy you can raise it up and it really
you know cuts down on that for you which
is really nice now with these leg
rollers right here
they're also adjustable as you can see
you have six different adjustments right
there there's a pin right here you just
pull this out you can do it on either
side doesn't matter and then you're able
to swing it up and down just wherever
you want so it's really nice that you
can completely tuck these leg rollers
out of the way whenever you're going to
do you know a basic flat bench press you
know whatever you can do that and this
is all just like personal preference on
comfort and really where you want that
to go now I really like this front foot
design
it's pretty narrow you know it's not
going to get in the way of your feet as
you're working out and that's just a
really nice touch and then this handle
right here in between these two leg
rollers which they're pretty soft
they're not going to hurt your shin or
anything this is great you know
especially you know if you raise these
leg rollers up it's super easy if I can
get this to go back in it's super easy
for you to grab that handle and move it
whenever you need to all right so we got
some dumbbells here I'm just gonna you
know show you guys a little bit how this
works so you want to go ahead and have
everything set up the way I want it just
want to go ahead and get in position
make sure your legs are locked in right
here and then you just lean on back and
then this is you know your decline bench
press
now you can also I think is really cool
is you know you can also use this bench
to work on your core you can sit here
and have this position like this and you
can sit here and work on you know your
sit-ups
and that's really nice as well now you
can seamlessly switch from decline to
Incline let's go ahead and put this back
down
go ahead and raise this up to 45 degrees
actually you know what we're gonna do
30.
you can do 45 degrees this is going to
hit the front of your shoulders a little
bit more
and then you're good to go for your
incline presses right here
and then lastly you know 45 degrees is
going to be good for the front of your
shoulders but I'm gonna go ahead and do
60.
should give me a little bit more you
know support on my back and I'm gonna go
ahead and move this leg roller out of
the way as well
because I don't need it right here
go ahead and put that out of the way
and then you're good to go
so this vintage is just really versatile
in my opinion the fact you're able to do
all these exercises just in you know a
couple seconds like I just did is just a
really nice touch to add to your home
gym
foreign
Fitness AB 3000 well if you're in the
market for a weight bench that's likely
going to last you a couple decades I
think you're really going to be happy
with the 11 gauge steel right here it's
also nice that rep throws in a 10-year
warranty on the frame of this bench you
know just for a little added security
blanket you know that's a really nice
touch if you're somebody who lifts a lot
of weight say you're you know an elite
power lifter I think you're also going
to really enjoy the fact that this bench
is rated to hold up to a thousand pounds
which is obviously a really high number
it's also super versatile so if you're
looking for a bench that has various
angles for you to work with you know and
always switch up your workouts I think
you're really going to like the
versatility of this bench right here and
then honestly if you're looking for the
best bang for your buck purchase in
terms of a weight bench I really think
you might have found your match right
here
and when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this bench I mean it
really just boils down to two different
things in my opinion first is the money
yes I just says probably the best bang
for your buck purchase with a weight
bench that is still true I still you
know am going to preach that but you
know at the same time not everybody
wants to spend 300 on just a weight
bench so if that's you maybe you don't
need a you know bench with a thousand
pound weight capacity maybe you don't
need the various angles whatever you can
definitely find you know a cheaper bench
out there in sticking with the fact I
mean maybe you don't need an adjustable
weight bench you know say you're a power
lifter say you know you compete in
competitions and you really don't need
an adjustable weight bench you're just
looking for something you know that
meets competition standards you know
something for you to work with at home
well then you like I said you probably
don't need a bench like this you're
probably gonna be better off with just a
basic flat bench
[Music]
thank you
well that's about all I have for you
guys today on the rep Fitness AB 3000
I've been thoroughly impressed with this
weight bench during my time with it you
know it's super versatile with the
various angles you have with the leg
roller the seat pad and the back pad
once again it's made from 11 gauge steel
so it's likely going to last you a
lifetime and it's got that super high
weight capacity of a thousand pounds
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was really helpful and that I
was able to show you exactly what to
expect with this weight bench as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com and you can
read more about this product all you
gotta do is search bar Bend rep Fitness
AB 3000 2.0 review and you'll find
everything we talked about here today in
further detail I'll catch y'all next
time
[Music]
thank you